Edward Ugwu

Software Engineer

An experienced front-end engineer with demonstrated expertise in React, Angular, HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Typescript, I specialize in developing responsive websites and web applications that provide a beautiful, intuitive user experience and drive maximum engagement and conversions. I have a keen eye for detail and have successfully applied my skills to the financial, e-commerce, and health care industries. With a passion for creating top-notch user experiences, I take pride in my work and always strive to create the best user experience possible.



Contact

Work

Work History

E-mail

nnvedward@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://linkedin.com/in/nnvemeka

www

https://nnvemeka.vercel.ap

Technical Profile

- JavaScript
- React
- Angular
- TypeScript
- HTML
- CSS
- C#
- ASP.NET
- Git
- Bootstrap
- SQL Server
- Postman
- Firebase
- MongoDB
- Express

2022-07 -Current

Frontend Engineer

Prexcribe, Abuja

- Made recommendations for new technology integration based on suitability and alignment to business goals.
- Increased web application usage by 35% by implementing unit tests.
- Liaised between marketing and IT on web development projects integrating front-end assets to back-end systems.
- Teamed on user-centric design strategy in translation of UX and business requirements into coded solutions.

2020-01 -2022-11

Software Developer

BlueTag Technologies Limited, Enugu

- Updated old code bases to modern development standards, improving functionality by 20%.
- Collaborated with project managers to select ambitious, but realistic coding milestones on pre-release software project development.
- Integrated constructive programs into cohesive product.
- Designed intuitive graphical user interfaces to improve user experience.
- Integrated software components into fully functional software system.

2022-01 -2022-06 Frontend Developer (Contract)

Kellispay, Lagos

 Planned and developed interfaces that simplified overall management and ease usage.

- Optimized website and increased speed by 15%.
- Built and deployed scalable mobile responsive User Interfaces for maximized User experience.
- Contributed ideas and suggestions in team meetings and delivered updates on deadlines, designs and enhancements.

Competencies

Web Design

Node.jsGitHub

Performance optimization

API design knowledge

Object-Oriented
Programming (OOP)

Organization and Time Management 2019-01 -2019-12 Frontend Engineer (Contract)

Davayte, Kazan

- Worked cooperatively with client services, sales and design team in deadline-driven environment.
- Designed and updated layouts to meet usability and performance requirements, increasing app speed by 10%.
- Coded using HTML, CSS and JavaScript to develop features for both mobile and desktop platforms.
- Improved tools to boost user interaction and deliver design versatility.

Social Perceptiveness

Communication

Analytic Problem-Solving

Responsive design

Cross-Browser Compatibility

Version Control

2018-04 -2018-09 Software Developer (IT)

Nigerian Breweries PLC, Lagos

- Built and deployed scalable mobile responsive User Interfaces for maximized User experience.
- Assisted with search engine optimization (SEO) strategies and techniques
- Worked with version control systems such as Git and SVN.
- Wrote well designed, testable and efficient code.
- Participated in code reviews to ensure best

Testing and Debugging

Adaptability

Leadership



English

practices.

Education

Bachelor of Science: Computer 2015-09 -2019-10

Science

Enugu State University of Science And Technology - Enugu

Certifications

2022-12 Meta: Advanced React

Udemy: Full stack development 2019-01